## KHANISH ALASGAROV



## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

**Phone:** +994 055 565 83 59 **Mail:** aleskeroov@gmail.com

Addess: Azerbaijan, Baku, 26th Hovsan str.

I have been working in the software industry for more than 1 year and my interest and passion for software development has never diminished during this time. Especially my experiences in developing backend applications with dotnet core and desktop applications with WPF helped me develop my deep knowledge and skills in the field of software development.

## **EXPERIENCE**

September 2022 - Now

Code Academy / Azerbaijan, Baku

Academic Mentor

At Code Academy, I provided support and guidance to students, especially helping them develop their programming skills. I guided students in their projects and helped them achieve their goals. I was actively involved in Lab classes and helped students with practical implementation and troubleshooting. I regularly monitored students' progress and provided the necessary resources to support their academic achievement. I created an effective learning environment among the students and motivated them by using my communication skills.

June 2023 - October 2023

Optima Group CO / Azerbaijan, Baku

Back-end Developer

As a Junior Backend and Desktop Developer at Optima, I consider this role as a crucial step in my software development career. Thanks to my experience and eagerness to learn, I have the opportunity to contribute significantly to projects. I have enhanced my foundational skills through participation in database design and backend business logic development. Additionally, I have refined my abilities by working on user interface designs and performance enhancements during the development of desktop applications.

SKILLS			
WPF	Expert	C#	Expert
ASP.NET Core	Expert	Microsoft SQL Server	Expert
ASP.NET Web API	Expert	ASP.NET MVC	Expert
HTML	Expert	CSS3	Expert
JavaScript	Expert	SASS	Expert
React.js	Expert	Git	Expert
Docker	Expert	Model-view-viewmodel (MVVM)	Expert
Entity Framework (EF) Core	Expert	SignalR	Expert

## **EDUCATION**

September 2021 - February 2022

Code Academy / Azerbaijan, Baku

The software development course I took at Codecademy played an important role in improving my basic software skills and creating a broader software development knowledge base. I turned this knowledge into practical applications through projects and assignments. The course also helped me become more skilled in software development processes, database design and user interface development. The knowledge and experiences I gained during this course allowed me to work successfully on real-world projects.

LINKS			
(in) khanishalasgarov			
(in the state of t			
LANGUAGES			
Azerbaijani			
Turkish			
English			
AWARDS			
Software Development Diploma from Code Academy			
Diploma of the all-republic tournament in martial arts of the Republic of Azerbaijan (1st Place)			
Combat Jiu-Jitsu International Federation Diploma (3st Place)			
HOBBIES			
Reading			
Swimming			
Video games			
Traveling			
PERSONAL INFO			
Date of birth: 29 December 2004			
Place of birth: Azerbaijan, Balaken			
Nationality: Azerbaijani			